Guide to the Rice University Department of Psychology records, 1977-2010 UA 347
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Department of Psychology records
1977-2010
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University
UA 347
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
Records of Dr. David Schneider's career at Rice University dealing with different aspects of Schneider's career and works. These subseries include letters, e-mails, papers, department data, and evaluations involving Schneider and other faculty within the Psychology Department.
Biographical / Historical
The Rice University Department of Psychology, opened in 1963, serves both undergraduate and graduate students, offering a B.A. as well as M.A. and Ph.D. education and training. Its primary focus is on research in both clinical and applied areas. The Department of Psychology is housed in Sewall Hall.
David Schneider came to Rice as a Professor of Psychology in 1989, and served as Department Chair from 1990-1996. He earned his B.A. of Psychology and Philosophy from Wabash College in 1962, and earned his Ph.D. of Social Psychology from Stanford University in 1966. His research interests included stereotypes, prejudice, and the categorization of people.
Scope and Contents
These records, dated from 1977-2010, have been divided into three subseries, each dealing with different aspects of Schneider's career and works. These subseries include letters, e-mails, papers, department data, and evaluations involving Schneider and other faculty within the Psychology Department.
Conditions Governing Access
Some materials are restricted due to the sensitive information contained therein. Each restricted folder is labeled. Written permission from the University Archivist is required for access. Contact woodson@rice.edu for assistance. Materials will be restricted until 2040.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to the Woodson Research Center in 2013.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Education
Document Types
reports; letters (correspondence); financial records
- Series I: David Schneider, Chair, 1977-2010; 173540
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 173541
    - Cards, Emails, and Memos, 1988-1998; 173544 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Continuing Education, 1990-1997; 173545 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters, 1987-1995; 173546 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters of Recommendation, 1996-2010; 173547 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Publications and Presentations, 173542
    - Editing, 1988-1995; 173548 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Mensa Gathering and Presentation, 1995; 173549 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Presentations and Lectures, 1992-1996; 173550 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Publications and Papers, 1977-2005; 173551 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C: Departmental Business, 173543
    - Annual Reports, 1995-2002; 173552 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Budget and Funds, 1996-1997; 173553 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Department Decisions, 2002; 173554 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Department and Faculty Meetings, 1990-1996; 173555 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Department Structure, 1998-1999; 173556 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Faculty Evaluations, 1993-2006; 173557 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Faculty Recruitment, 1996-1999; 173558 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Foundations of Social Sciences Course, 1989-1994; 173559 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Graduate Program, 1996-1999; 173560 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - History of Psychology Course, 1995-2002; 173561 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Program Proposals, 1999; 173562 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Psychology Faculty Citations, 1982-1996; 173563 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Space Issues, 1993-2000; 173564 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Strategic Planning, 1996; 173565 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Undergraduate Curriculum Reform, 1993-2000; 173566 (Box 2, Folder 15)